BABATUNDE **ATIJOSAN**

Frontend Software Developer

Phone: +2349034775269

Email: atijosanbabatunde@gmail.com

Accomplished senior software developer with four years of experience leading projects by acting as architect, developer, and programmer analyst. Proficient in supporting project deliverables and maintaining releases. A strong leader in guiding support teams and solving complex issues. Steadfast in planning and implementing effective development strategies based on industry best practices.

Technical profile

HTML | JavaScript | Microsoft word | CSS | GIT | JIRA | Bootstrap | React | Docker | Node.js

TypeScript || GitHub || Postman

competencies

Code validation

User documentation

Software Development Life cycle

User requirements analysis

Product development

Work History

2022-05 - 2022-10 Senior Software Developer

INNOVATE GLOBAL, United Kingdom

- Built, implemented, and maintained web-based user-friendly interface applications.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Consulted with engineering team members to determine system loads and develop improvement plans.
- Coordinated efficient large-scale software developments.
- Provided technical support using knowledge of complex technology to solve problems and support new projects.
- Built reusable codes and libraries.
- Optimized web application for maximum speed and scability.
- Monitored ongoing operation of assigned programs and responded to problems by diagnosing and correcting logic and coding errors.

2021-02 - 2022-08 Frontend Software Developer

TECHPET GLOBAL, NIGERIA

- A member of the team that developed Appera, a cloud-based collaboration and project management tool suitable for businesses of all sizes and industries.
- Facilitated the merging of pull requests on git created by the interns.

- Participated in team-building activities to enhance the working relationship.
- Participated in continuous improvement by generating suggestions, engaging in problem-solving activities to support teamwork.
- Proved successful working within tight deadlines and a fast-paced atmosphere.
- Learned new skills and applied them to daily tasks to improve efficiency and productivity.
- Experience writing unit and integration tests using cypress.

2021-08 - 2022-02 Frontend Software Developer

GOFLEX, Lagos, Nigeria

- Developed a dashboard to Interact with Customers, Lenders, agents, and merchants.
- Participated in team-building activities to enhance working relationships.
- Worked within applicable standards, policies, and regulatory guidelines to promote a safe working environment.
- Management and integration of API (POSTMAN).
- Documenting each page using Confluence and readme.
- Increased customer satisfaction by resolving issues

2019-02 - 2020-11 Website Developer

BEDGE CONCEPT, Lagos, Nigeria

- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX, and JSON Coding.
- Designed, implemented, and monitored web pages, plugins, and functionality for continuous improvement.
- Collaborated with marketing, representing the web team to establish project goals, projections, and milestones.
- Optimized the company's website and main cooperate blog to boost SEO traffic to sites.
- Multi-tasked across multiple functions and roles to meet deadlines and organizational expectations.
- Built and styled a new mobile-friendly website, transitioning legacy presentations to simultaneous easy-to-use versions.

Education

2015-01 - 2019-04 Bachelor Of Science - BS: Computer Science

LAGOS STATE UNIVERSITY- Lagos Nigeria

Activities and societies:, Science). Lasutech developers' group Computer Science Student Association (PROGRAMMERS TEAM).

Faculty of Social Science Tech Exco. (Technical Support Team).